The idea for Hidden Markov Models is the following: Let's
介绍下隐马尔可夫模型的原理
say that a way of tagging the sentence "Jane will spot
假设标记句子“Jane will spot Will”的方式是
Will" is noun-modal-verb-noun and
名词-情态动词-动词-名词
we'll calculate a probability associated with this tagging.
我们将计算该标记的概率
So we need two things.
我们需要计算两种概率
First of all, how likely is it that a noun is followed by
首先 名词后面是情态动词
a modal and a modal by a verb and a verb by a noun.
情态动词后面是动词 动词后面是名词的概率是多少
These need to be high in order for this tagging to be likely.
这个概率必须很高 这样这个标记才有可能发生
These are called the transition probabilities.
这些概率称之为转移概率
Now, the second set of probabilities we need to
我们要计算的另一组概率是
calculate are these: What is the probability that
名词将为 Jane
a noun will be the word Jane and that a modal will be the word will, etc.
情态动词将为 will 等等的概率
This also need to be relatively high for our tagging to be likely.
这个概率也必须相对很高 这样这个标记才有可能发生
These are called the Emission Probabilities.
这些概率称之为发射概率
So, here are sentences with
这些是包含对应标签的句子
their corresponding tags and we're going to calculate the Emission Probabilities,
我们将计算发射概率
that is the probability that if a word is, say,
即如果单词是名词
a noun that that word will be Mary or Jane, etc.
该单词将是 Mary 或 Jane 等的概率
So, to do this we again do a counting table like this one where, for example,
为此 我们将创建一个这样的表格
the entry on the Mary row and the noun column is
例如 Mary 所在行和名词所在列的值是 4
four because Mary appears four times as a noun.
因为 Mary 出现为名词四次
Now, in order to find the probabilities,
为了计算概率
we divide each column by the sum of the entries and we obtain the following numbers.
我们将每列除以条目之和 获得这些数字
And here's a graphical representation of this table.
我们用图形表示这个表格
Say, if we know that a word is a noun,
假设如果知道某个单词是名词
the probabilities of it being Mary is four over nine,
它是 Mary 的概率是 4/9
Jane is two over nine,
Jane 的概率是 2/9
Will is one over nine,
Will 的概率是 1/9
and Spot is two over nine.
Spot 的概率是 2/9
The other words are zero.
其他单词的概率是 0
Same thing for modal, and for verb.
情态动词和动词的计算流程一样
And notice that words can appear repeatedly here like
注意 单词可以重复出现
Will which appears as a noun and also as a modal.
例如 Will 即是名词又是情态动词
That is no problem.
这样没问题
So, now let's calculate the transition probabilities.
我们现在计算转移概率
These are the probabilities that are part of speech follows another part of speech.
即某个词性在另一个词性后面的概率
First, in order to actually get the whole picture,
首先 为了了解整个情况
we'll add starting and ending tags on
我们将在每个句子上添加起始标签和结束标签
each sentence and we'll treat these tags as parts of speech as well.
并且将这些标签也当做词性
And now we make a table of counts in this table.
现在创建计数表
We count the number of appearances of each pair of parts of speech.
我们计算每个词性的出现次数
For example, this three here in the noun row and the modal column
例如 名词行和情态动词列的这个 3
corresponds to the three occurrences of a noun followed by a modal.
表示名词后面是情态动词的发生次数为 3
Now, to find the probabilities,
现在 为了计算概率
we divide each row by the sum of the entries in the row.
我们将每行除以行中条目的和
In this way, if we look at,
这样的话
say, the modal row,
对于情态动词行
the probability that the next part of speech is a noun is one quarter,
下个词性是名词的概率是 1/4
but it's a verb it's three quarters and that
是动词的概率是 3/4
it's a modal or the end of the sentence is zero.
在句子结束是情态动词的概率是 0
And here's a nice graph of our transition probabilities.
这个就是转移概率的图形
We draw our parts of speech and arrows between
我们绘出词性并在词性之间添加箭头
them with the transition probabilities attached to them,
同时附上转移概率
and as a final step we combine the two previous graphs to form a Hidden Markov Model.
最后一步是将前两个图形组合到一起 形成隐马尔可夫模型
We have our words, which are observations.
我们有单词 即观察结果
These are called the observations because they are
称之为观察结果是因为
the things we observe when we read the sentences.
它们是我们在阅读句子时观察到的事物
And the parts of speech are called the Hidden States,
词性称之为隐藏状态
since they are the ones we don't know and we have to infer based on the words.
因为它们是未知信息 我们需要根据单词进行推理
And among the Hidden States we have the transmission probabilities,
在隐藏状态中存在转移概率
and between the Hidden States and the observation we have the Emission Probabilities.
在隐藏状态和观察结果之间存在发射概率
And that's it. That's a Hidden Markov Model.
这就是隐马尔可夫模型